Guide to the California Asian American Artists Biographical Survey Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
- California Artists Files (entry artists), Series 1
  - Leong, James (Box 10, Folder 10)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; FAMSF exhibition information; SFAA exhibition information; notes from interview with artist; biographical materials from artist, including resume; articles.
  - Lim Tsing-ai (Lin Ching-ni) (Box 10, Folder 11)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; articles. Lim Tsing-ai was a San Francisco gallery owner and ink painter 1950s-60s.
  - Liu, James Yeh-jau (Box 10, Folder 12)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; articles; photos; correspondence; examples of artwork.
  - Lowe, Peter (Box 11, Folder 1)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; Chinatown Artist Club information; photocopies of Oakland Museum records; FAMSF exhibition information; SFAA exhibition information; transcription of interview with artist and other interview transcripts.
  - Luke, Keye (Box 11, Folder 2)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; LA Times Index citation; misc. exhibition information; articles; death certificate.
  - Mancao, Frank A. (Box 11, Folder 3)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; census records. Frank A. Mancao was a photographer of the Filipino community in Reedly, CA.
  - Markino, Yoshio (Box 11, Folder 4)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; SFAI enrollment info; info from Japanese publications, including some translations; articles.
  - Mateo, Sylvester P. (Box 11, Folder 5)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; FAMSF exhibition information; SFAA exhibition information; photographs of artist and his artwork; photocopies of vintage images and other archival materials.
  - Matsubara, Kazuo (Box 11, Folder 6)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; SFAI enrollment records; misc. exhibition records; SFAA exhibition information; articles; census records.
  - May's Photo Studio (Yai S. Lee and Isabelle May Lee) (Box 11, Folder 7)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; articles; examples of photographs; publication, The Pear Garden in the West.
  - Miyagi, Yotoku (Box 11, Folder 8)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; articles; SFAI enrollment records.
  - Miyagi, Yotoku - book, Yotoku Miyagi: Light and Shade of An Immigrant Artist (in Japanese) (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Miyasaki, George (Box 11, Folder 10)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; SFMOMA exhibition information; FAMSF exhibition information; catalogs; resume and other biographical materials from artist; correspondence; transcript of interview.
  - Miyatake, Toyo (Box 12, Folder 1)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; photocopies of internment camp newspapers; newpaper articles and other published materials.
  - Miyatake, Toyo - copies of interview transcript from Claremont Graduate University (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Miyazaki, Shiro (Box 12, Folder 3)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; FAMSF exhibition information; SFAA exhibition information; census records.
  - Morimoto, Charles Isamu (Box 12, Folder 4)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; photocopies of internment camp newspaper, Manzanar Free Press; census records; articles; misc. exhibition records.
  - Nakanishi, Kinichi (Box 12, Folder 5)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; misc. exhibition records; census records; relocation center census sheet.
  - Nakano, Emiko (Box 12, Folder 6)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; SFMOMA exhibition information; FAMSF exhibition information; SFAA exhibition information; correspondence; census records.
  - Nanao, Kenjilo (Box 12, Folder 7)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; SF General Hospital collection publication; catalogs; notes from interview; resume; articles.
  - Ng, Win (Box 12, Folder 8)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; FAMSF exhibition information; SFAA exhibition information; photos of artwork; articles; catalog; notes from interview with family.
  - Nishi, Ken (Box 12, Folder 9)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; resume; catalog; articles.
  - Nobuyuki, Kiyoo Harry (Box 12, Folder 10)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; SFMOMA exhibition information; misc. exhibition records; FAMSF exhibition information; SFAA exhibition information; census records.
  - Noda, Hideo Benjamin (Box 12, Folder 11)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; photocopies from Japanese publications (some translated); FAMSF exhibition information; SFAA exhibition information; photocopies of materials from Archives of American Art.
  - Noda, Hideo Benjamin - materials from the Woodstock Art Association (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Noguchi, Isamu (Box 13, Folder 1)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; LA Times Index citation; Ferdinand Perret files; photocopied materials from Hoover Institution and the Archives of American Art; articles.
  - Nomiyama, Koichi (Box 13, Folder 2)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; SFMOMA exhibition information; photocopies of internment camp newspaper, Granada Pioneer; misc. exhibition information; FAMSF exhibition information; relocation camp departure index; SFAA exhibition information.
  - Nong (Robert Han) (Box 13, Folder 3)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; photocopies of Oakland Museum records; correspondence with artist; notes from interview; catalog.
  - Obata, Chiura (Box 13, Folder 4)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; LA Times Index citation; Internment records; correspondence with artist's family; catalog; materials from family including photocopies of Obata's writings; articles.
  - Obata, Chiura - correspondence, oral history transcript (Box 13, Folder 5)
    Transcipt of interview from UCLA special collections.
  - Okamoto, Yajiro (Box 13, Folder 6)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; SFMOMA exhibition information; misc. exhibition information; SFAA exhibition information; census records; internment records.
  - Okamura, Arthur Shinji (Box 13, Folder 7)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; FAMSF exhibition information; SFAA exhibition information; resume.
  - Okubo, Benji (Box 13, Folder 8)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; photocopies of internment camp newspaper, Heart Mountain Sentinel; relocation camp departure index; articles; information on Japanese American National Museum holdings.
  - Okubo, Mine (Box 13, Folder 9)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; FAMSF exhibition information; relocation camp departure index; Internment camp newspapers; catalog; articles; information regarding her memorial service in Bay Area.
  - Okubo, Mine - correspondence with Okubo, publications (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Park, Charles (Box 14, Folder 2)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; articles; census records; materials provided by great-granddaughter.
  - Park, Lanhei Kim (Box 14, Folder 3)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; photos of artwork; excerpts of autobiography "Facing Four Ways."
  - Poon, Irene (Box 14, Folder 4)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; articles; examples of artwork; resume.
  - Quon, Milton (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Sato, Riyo (Box 14, Folder 6)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; SFMOMA exhibition information; photocopies of internment camp newspaper, Heart Mt. Sentinel; FAMSF exhibition information; SFAA exhibition information; information about artwork in FAMSF collection.
  - Sekimachi, Kay (Box 14, Folder 7)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; photocopies of Oakland Museum records; FAMSF exhibition information; transcripts of interview; correspondence from artist; resume; transcript of Archives of American Art interview; catalogs.
  - Serisawa, Sueo (Box 14, Folder 8)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; LA Times Index citation; misc. exhibition records; photocopies of internment camp newspaper, Heart Mt. Sentinel; FAMSF exhibition information; SFAA exhibition information; examples of artwork; articles; transcript of interview.
  - Shibata, Yayoi Ailene (Box 14, Folder 9)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; SFAA exhibition information; articles; resume, and other info from artist.
  - Sogioka, Gene I. (Box 14, Folder 10)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; Relocation center census sheet; SFAA exhibition information; photocopies of internment camp newspapers; correspondence with artist's family; articles.
  - Sugimoto, Henry (Box 14, Folder 11)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; Relocation center census sheet; misc. exhibition records; videotape documentary; FAMSF exhibition information; relocation camp departure index; SFAA exhibition information.
  - Sugimoto, Henry - press (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Sugimoto, Henry - interviews, biographical manuscripts (Box 15, Folder 2)
    Transcripts of interviews with artist; biographical writings from artist.
  - Suski, Julia (Box 15, Folder 3)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; illustrations from the LA Japanese Daily News newspaper; census records.
  - Suzuki, James (Jimi) H. (Box 15, Folder 4)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; correspondence with artist; articles; photocopies of Oakland Museum records; SFMOMA exhibition information.
  - Suzuki, Lewis (Box 15, Folder 5)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; photocopies from internment camp newspaper; information from artist including articles and examples of artwork.
  - Suzuki, Sakari (Box 15, Folder 6)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; photocopies of internment camp newspapers; SFAI enrollment records; SFAA exhibition information; immigration records; articles; examples of artwork.
  - Suzuki, Shunryu (Box 15, Folder 7)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; example of artwork; photocopy from exhibition brochure.
  - Taira, Frank (Box 15, Folder 8)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; relocation camp departure index; SFAA exhibition information; photocopies of internment camp newspapers; correspondence with artist; resume; photographs of artwork and other materials from artist.
  - Takahashi, Katsuzo (Box 15, Folder 9)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; misc. exhibition information including, Mechanics Institute exhibitions, World's Columbian Expo, Chicago, 1893. Translation of information from Japanese publications; information on Eshun, Buddhist nun who is subject of painting; examples of artwork.
  - Takayama, Michio (Box 15, Folder 10)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; catalogs, photos and other information from family; articles.
  - Takemoto, Henry (Box 16, Folder 1)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; articles; examples of artwork.
  - Tam, Reuben (Box 16, Folder 2)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; FAMSF exhibition information; SFAA exhibition information; articles; catalogs; slide.
  - Tam, Reuben - photocopies of materials from the Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Tape, Mary (Box 16, Folder 4)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; photo of artist; family information.
  - Terada, Takeo Edward (Box 16, Folder 5)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; misc. exhibition information; FAMSF exhibition information; information from Japanese publications (some translated); SFAA exhibition information; articles; information regarding artist's mural at Coit Tower.
  - Teraoka, Masami (Box 16, Folder 6)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; correspondence with artist; articles; examples of artwork; resume.
  - Thiel, Midori Kono (Box 16, Folder 7)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; SFAA exhibition information; notes from interview with artist; SFMOMA exhibition information; articles.
  - Tominaga, Chio (Box 16, Folder 8)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; notes from conversation with daughter; catalog.
  - Tse, Wing Kwong (Box 16, Folder 9)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; FAMSF exhibition information; articles; examples of artwork and photos of artist; correspondence; information from niece.
  - Tseng, Yuho (Betty Ecke) (Box 16, Folder 10)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; catalogs; article; information from artist; information on murals.
  - Tsuzuki, Byron Takashi (Box 17, Folder 1)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; Relocation center census sheet; articles.
  - Uetsuji, Kitaro (Box 17, Folder 2)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; photocopies of internment camp newspapers; Relocation center census sheet; articles; misc. exhibition information.
  - Ueyama, Tokio (Box 17, Folder 3)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; misc. exhibition information; SFAI enrollment records; SFAA exhibition information; articles; FAMSF exhibition information; internment camp newspapers; Relocation Center census sheet; photocopies of publications from Japan.
  - Uno, Sadayuki Thomas (Box 17, Folder 4)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; notes from conversation with daughter; immigration records. Sadayuki Uno studied at the California College of Arts and Crafts in Oakland prior to WWII, and painted while interned at Jerome and Rohwer.
  - Uyeno, Sekishun Masuzo (Box 17, Folder 5)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; city directory records; articles; census records.
  - Vallangca, Roberto (Box 17, Folder 6)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; SFAA exhibition information; notes following conversation with artist's widow.
  - Valledor, Leo (Box 17, Folder 7)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; transpcript of interview; SFMOMA exhibition information; articles; catalog; resume and artist's statement.
  - Villa, Carlos (Box 17, Folder 8)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; FAMSF exhibition information; transcript of interview; articles; resume.
  - Villa, Carlos - catalogs, brochures, postcards (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Villa, Carlos - artist's writings, projects (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Wang, C.C. (Wang, Chi-Ch'ien, Wang Jiqian) (Box 17, Folder 11)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; photocopy of catalog; obituary.
  - Watanabe, Torajiro (Box 18, Folder 1)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; articles; examples of artwork; misc. exhibition information.
  - Weakland, Anna Wu (Box 18, Folder 2)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; FAMSF exhibition information; catalogs.
  - Wong, Charles (Box 18, Folder 3)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; SFMOMA exhibition information; SFAA exhibition information; catalog; articles; transcript of interview; examples of artwork.
  - Wong, Jade Snow (Connie Ong) (Box 18, Folder 4)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; FAMSF exhibition information; SFMOMA exhibition information; articles; materials from artist including correspondences.
  - Wong, Lui-sang (Box 18, Folder 5)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; correspondence; photocopied information from Chinese publication.
  - Wong, Martin (Box 18, Folder 6)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; photographs of artist and artwork; photocopies of artist's writings; correspondenc; misc. exhibition records; resume.
  - Wong, Martin - catalogs, exhibitions announcements, postcards (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Wong, Martin - correspondence from Florence Fie (artist's mother) (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Wong, Martin - exhibition proposals (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Wong, Nanying Stella (Box 19, Folder 1)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; Chinatown Artists Club information; misc. exhibition information; correspondence from artist; photographs of artist and artwork.
  - Wong, Tyrus (Box 19, Folder 2)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; misc. exhibition information; SFAA exhibition information; catalogs; photos of artist and artwork; transcript of Archives of American Art interview; LA Times Index citation; articles; FAMSF exhibition information; info from artist and artist's family.
  - Woo, Gary (Box 19, Folder 3)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; SFMOMA exhibition information; photocopies from LACMA files; SFAA exhibition information; notes from interview; catalogs; examples of artwork; resume; articles.
  - Woo, Jade Fon (Jade Fon) (Box 19, Folder 4)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; Chinatown Artists Club information; misc. exhibition information; SFAA exhibition information; California State Fair and LA County Fair information; LA Times Index; photocopies of Oakland Museum records; resume; articles; correspondence with artist's friend.
  - Yamamoto, Noriko (Box 19, Folder 5)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; SFMOMA exhibition information; photos of artwork; info from artist including resume; FAMSF exhibition information; photocopy of catalog.
  - Yamasaki, Jack Chikamichi (Box 19, Folder 6)
    Photocopies of biographical sourcees; SFAI enrollment info; SFAA exhibition information; articles.
  - Yang, Chao-chen (Box 19, Folder 7)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; photocopies of artist's papers in the Archives of American Art including photocopies of resume, interview, and photos; articles.
  - Yang, Ling-Fu (Box 19, Folder 8)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; articles; photocopies from her books; photographs of artwork.
  - Yashima, Mitsu (Tomoe Iwamatsu) (Box 19, Folder 9)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; articles; photos of artwork; transcript of phone conversation with artist's son.
  - Yashima, Taro (Jun Atushi Iwamatsu) (Box 20, Folder 1)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; photocopies of internment camp newspapers; misc. exhibition information; transcript of phone conversation with artist's son; info regarding artist's papers at Univ of Southern Mississippi; photocopies of books.
  - Yip, Richard D. (Box 20, Folder 2)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; misc. exhibition records including Cal State Fair and California Watercolor Society; FAMSF exhibition information; SFAA exhibition information; examples of artwork; articles.
  - Yong, Lai (Box 20, Folder 3)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; city directory records; examples of artwork; articles; census records.
  - Yoshida, Sekido (Box 20, Folder 4)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; SFMOMA exhibition information; misc.exhibition information; SFAA exhibition information; FAMSF exhibition information; city directories; photocopy of biography in Calif Art Research Monographs.
  - Yuan, S. C. (Si-chen Yuan, Wellington S. C. Yuan) (Box 20, Folder 5)
    Photocopies of biographical sources; SFMOMA exhibition information; FAMSF exhibition information; examples of artwork.
  - Alvarado, Ricardo Ocreto (Box 21, Folder 1)
    Audiotape inteview with artist's daughter.
  - Asawa, Ruth (Box 21, Folder 2)
    CD containing photographs Garden of Remembrance Dedication Ceremony April 19, 2002.
  - Carvajal, Sr., Carlos (Box 21, Folder 3)
    VHS tape interview "Carlos Carvajal, Jr. Saturday 6; 18; 94, reel 1 original." Videotape of interview with artist's son, Carlos Carvajal Jr.
  - Chan, Eva Fong (Box 21, Folder 4)
    Audiotapes (2) - interview with Eva Fong Chan for Chinese Women of America 1848-1982 Research Project at UC Santa Cruz. (Typed notes accompany audiotapes.)
  - Chang Shu-chi (Zhang Shuqi) (Box 21, Folder 5)
    Audiotape inteview with Gordon Chang (son of Chang Shu-chi) Oct 26, 1998. Digital files of artwork by Chang Shu-chi. (With notes detailing contents)
  - Chann, George (Chen Yinpi) (Box 21, Folder 6)
    CD with images of artwork.
  - Chinn, Benjamen, 9 computer file(s) (JPG)
  - Fujita, Sadamitsu Neil (Box 21, Folder 8)
    2 cassette tapes of interview with Sadamitsu Neil Fujita.
  - Harada, Taneyuki Dan (Box 22, Folder 1)
    Microcassette of interview with Taneyuki Dan Harada.
  - Hasegawa, Saburo, 1 optical disc(s) (CD) (Box 22, Folder 2)
    Audio CD: Edward Lieber, Music to Paintings, with compositions inspired by the art of Hasegawa. Letter which accompanied CD from Lieber.
  - Hibi, Hisako, 1 optical disc(s) (CD) (Box 22, Folder 3)
    Music CD Earth Prayer, by Russel Baba with cover art by Hisako Hibi.
  - Ishida, Nitten (Box 22, Folder 4)
    Digital videotcassette (mini DV) of interview with artist's daughter, Helen.
  - Jayo, Federico Dukoy (Box 22, Folder 5)
    Audiotape interview with artist's son, Norman Jayo and images of artwork.
  - Kee, Hu Wai (Key, H. W.) photographs, 4 computer file(s)
  - Kingman, Dong (Box 22, Folder 7)
    Videotape footage of film The World of Dong Kingman by James Wong Howe.
  - Kobashigawa, Hideo (Box 22, Folder 8)
    3 audiotapes of interview with artist's brother, Dick Jiro Kobashigawa and nephew, Ben Kobashigawa. CD with images of self-portrait paintings by artist.
  - Kwok, John (Box 22, Folder 9)
    Audiotapes (2) of interviews with artist's widow and son. CD with images of Kwok's work from Chinese American Museum exhibition.
  - Leong, Gilbert (Box 23, Folder 1)
    Audiotapes (2) of interview with Leslie Leong (daughter of artist).
  - Miyagi, Yotoku (Box 23, Folder 2)
    Videotape of Japanese documentary. Audiotape narration in English of events in documentary. Handwritten notes in English summarizing documentary.
  - Obata, Chiura (Box 23, Folder 3)
    Videotape: Obata Chiura and his Comrades. (Japanese television program.)
  - Quon, Milton (Box 23, Folder 4)
    Microcassette tape (1) with interview with Milton Quon. Transcript of inteview.
  - Sekimachi, Kay (Box 23, Folder 5)
    Cassette tapes (2) of interview with Kay Sekimachi.
  - Takayama, Michio (Box 23, Folder 6)
    Audiotape (1) interview with artist's grandaughter, Wako Takayama.
  - Tape, Mary, 2 computer file(s) (TIFF)
    CD with digital file of newspaper article, Our Chinese Edison.
  - Tseng, Yuho (Betty Ecke) mural images and related articles
  - Wong, Martin hi-res image of artwork, Polaris., 1 computer file(s) (TIFF)
  - Liu, James Yeh-jau (Box 24, Folder 1)
    Oversized book, The Paintings of Yeh-jau Liu.
  - May's Photo Studio (Yai S. Lee and Isabelle May Lee) (Box 24, Folder 2)
    Oversized catalog containing an image by May's Photo Studio.
  - Tseng, Yuho (Betty Ecke) (Box 24, Folder 3)
    Oversized printed announcement of World Savings mural by Tseng Yuho, supplied by Marian Sandler.
- California Artists Files (non-entry artists), Series 2
  Files on 1,222 artists not included in the biographical entry portion of Asian American Art: A History, 1850-1970. Contents of files predominantly are photocopies of secondary biographical source materials, photocopies of newspaper articles, and spreadsheets or other compiled documents produced by project researchers, with related and original source materials found in series 4. In many cases a file in series 2 may only contain one document. There is no detailed description of the content of files in this finding aid.
  - Abe, Satoru (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Adachi, S. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Ahashi, Karou (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Akaike, Hajime (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Akimoto, George (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Akiyama, T. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Amato, Sam (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Ameniya, R. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Andow, Kunie (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Aoki, Henry (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Arai (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Araki, Y. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Arashiro, Yonemitsu (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Ariye, Yoshiko (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Asahi, I. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Asaishi, K. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Asami, Sam (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Asayama, Koichi (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Asoma, Tadashi (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Asuma, Norio (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Barrios, Benny (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Bautista, Helen Martin (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Bepp, Kiroku (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Bicknell, George A. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Bowling, Mary (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Carvajal, Leondardo E. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Cassill, Jean Kubota (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Chan, Gloria (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Chan, K.S. (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Chan, Longsum (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Chan, Siu (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Chan, Stephen J. (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Chan, T.G. (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Chan, Wahso (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Chan, William (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Chang, Aileen (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Chang, Chung-ho (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Chang, Dai Song (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Chang, Fai Sue (Box 1, Folder 39)